# **ELIANE COHEN**

50 W 97<sup>th</sup> St. Apt 7L, New York, NY 10025 • (786) 317-0990 • coheneliane@gmail.com

## **PROFILE & CAREER HIGHLIGHTS**

Trilingual (English/Spanish/French) professional and acute problem-solver with four years of experience in private banking, nearly three years as Private Banker with \$120 million in assets under management of high net-worth clients, highly capable of relaying information clearly and in a convincing manner tailored to my specific audience. Looking to transition my Business Development skills beyond the banking industry.

- I exhibit **loyalty** and a **team** approach. Received client and colleague feedback touting professionalism, thorough attention to detail, honesty and integrity
- I am **ambitious** in generating new ideas and approaches to take advantage of opportunities. Took over a neglected portfolio with low ROA and turned it into a profitable portfolio of satisfied clients
- I am effective and creative. Raised portfolio ROA by 0.23% in the first year and maintained it within 0.86% 0.91%
- I am driven. Promoted from Assistant to Officer in under two years
- I am reliable. Selected for Disaster Recovery Testing in NY, representing all of front office
- · Placed first in monthly commissions and in portfolio turnover for my segment, multiple months
- Named "Best PBA (Private Banking Assistant) of 2009"
- Series 7 & Series 63

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Relationship Officer - BANK HAPOALIM, Miami FL

Jul 2010 - Feb 2013

- Managed existing and developed new relationships with high net-worth individuals providing excellent service tending
  to specific client needs, furnishing investment advice, balancing portfolios, preparing and presenting tailored investment
  proposals, and executing trades
- Traveled periodically to Argentina to visit clients and plan business development with counterparts from Uruguay
- Impeccably handled compliance and enhanced due diligence matters

## Private Banking Assistant - BANK HAPOALIM, Miami FL

Dec 2008 - Jul 2010

- Provided support to Private Bankers, sole PBA allowed to execute unsolicited client orders (Mar–Jul 2010)
- Achieved significant involvement as Secretary of the Investment Committee, Member of the Training Committee, Content Manager of the BHI Portal Initiative, and by creating the PBA Manual for new hires and current employees

## Executive Assistant - ALEF AMERICA INC., Miami FL

Jun – Aug 2007 & May – Aug 2006

 Acted as direct contact to clients and suppliers, managed end-to-end exportation of goods, created a matrix to analyze ROI and Cash Flow for each client and product

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

**TRAVEL** 

Apr – Sep 2013

Traveled internationally throughout the years, and recent five-month travel through South America, USA, Australia and New Zealand, broadened my cultural awareness and sensitivity, which allow me to relate and work with people from different ages, backgrounds and cultures. I am **versatile** and traveling has further strengthened my ability to quickly adapt to unforeseen situations, my negotiation skills, and my self-confidence.

## **INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS SOCIETY at UF**, Gainesville FL

Jan 2005 – May 2008

*Vice President, Secretary, Promotions & Marketing Director, and Member*. Recruited 30+ and managed 60+ members, and an 18-member executive board. Planned and led weekly meetings focused on the World market economy and global politics, promoted study abroad and guided members in program selection and financing, organized and participated in community service projects and sporting events.

• Created and led the "... because Gators are Green" Fundraiser

Aug 2007 – May 2008

Sold sustainable grocery bags to reduce plastic consumption in local supermarkets. Received the Warrington College of Business Administration Award for "Outstanding Program of the Year"

## **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA, Gainesville FL

Jun 2004 - May 2008

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Major in Marketing

Certificate in Mass Communication Studies, Minor in French, Named multiple times to the Dean's List

**CERAM**, Sophia Antipolis, France, Overseas Studies

Jan – May 2007